Sean Mandable

Senior Software Engineer

(475) 231-5287

sean@seanmandable.me

(A)

www.seanmandable.me





I'm a full stack developer with experience building web applications using the latest technologies. I like learning new things! I have expertise with both front and back end technologies and languages.

With a strong eye for design and exacting attention to detail, I'm the one whose eyes immediately go to the typo or the often—misused "there", "they're", "its", "it's"— or the image that is just *one* pixel misaligned.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Freelance Senior Software Engineer

Freelance | 2008 - Present

I'm experienced with the full development life cycle from design to implementation, testing, and deployment. I apply SEO, web security and performance standards and best practices wherever possible. I've done everything from developing and implementing a user management system in PHP/MySQL to creating a WordPress widget to read and display data from streaming music providers. One wears many different hats!

Drupal Web Developer

North American Power | 2017

I was responsible for the look and feel of NAP's enrollment website redesign. I did everything from working on visual design elements to Sass/SCSS authoring, updates and refactoring. I wrote a lot of JavaScript to provide various functionality. This was using Foundation 6 and Drupal 7. I helped select and then implement tools and technologies to support business needs. I also participated in daily scrum meetings and worked to improve code efficiency and readability while reducing redundancy.

Senior Software Engineer

DiscoverOrg | 2014 - 2016

I was involved in the entire DiscoverOrg 2.0 software development life cycle, end to end. I was responsible for the look and feel of the new site, which included selecting and then implementing appropriate technologies to produce the desired behaviors. I created new Angular views in HTML and SCSS along with required models and controllers in JavaScript. I both consumed existing Java APIs and wrote my own. I maintained the existing application and fixed a host of assorted issues. I also refactored JavaScript, PHP, PERL, HTML, and CSS to improve the look, feel, functionality, and performance.

Front-end Developer

Blue World | 2013 - 2014

Built a large web application using Bootstrap, JQuery and PHP. Implemented new functionality for existing sites on a PHP backend using JQuery, HTML and CSS. Refactored large codebase to increase efficiency and decrease page-load times.

Front-end Developer

Direct Wines | 2012 - 2013

Conceived, designed, implemented and delivered both corporate websites and web applications. Enhanced and maintained four e-commerce websites on an Oracle ATG backend, writing front-end functionality as well as custom JSTL functions. Produced original HTML, CSS, and graphics.

PROJECTS

Sean's MovieDB Open Source

This is an Angular/PHP/MySQL application to track my movie library. It lists movie titles, along with their duration, dimensions, and file size. It will fix filenames on disk to be in title case, move duplicate files, and a lot more. I'd call this a "minimally viable product" at this point.

deObfuscate Open Source

Fixes obfuscated filenames by renaming them to the name of the directory they are contained in. A directory named "ShowTitle.S01E01.1080p.HDTV.x264-AVS" containing a file named "ShowTitle.S01E01.1080p.HDTV.x264-AVS" would result in a file named "ShowTitle.S01E01.mp4" with the parent directory removed.

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript

Angular

jQuery

PHP

Apache

MySQL & MariaDB

npm

HTML & CSS

Sass

Design & user experience

Professional

Effective communication

Attention to detail

Self Sufficient

Quick learner

EDUCATION

MS, Interactive Media Communications

Quinnipiac University

BS, Management Information Systems

Albertus Magnus College

INTERESTS

Long-distance hiking

Reading

Skiing

Travelling